Life's a Party. Crash It.
Wedding Crashers is a comedy, romance film directed by David Dobkin.
John and his buddy, Jeremy are emotional criminals who know how to use
a woman's hopes and dreams for their own carnal gain.
Their modus operandi: crashing weddings.
Normally, they meet guests who want to toast the
romantic day with a random hook-up.
But when John meets Claire, he discovers what true
love – and heartache – feels like.
John Beckwith, played by Owen Wilson.
Jeremy Grey, played by Vince Vaughn.
Secretary Cleary, played by Christopher Walken.
Claire Cleary, played by Rachel McAdams.
Gloria Cleary, played by Isla Fisher.
Kathleen Cleary, played by Jane Seymour.
Wedding Crashers is a 2005 American romantic comedy film directed by David Dobkin, written by Steve Faber and Bob Fisher, starring Owen
Wilson, Vince Vaughn, Rachel McAdams and Isla Fisher with Christopher Walken, Bradley Cooper and Jane Seymour in supporting roles.
The film follows two divorce mediators (Wilson and Vaughn) who
crash weddings in an attempt to meet and seduce women.
When they crash the wedding of the U.S.
Treasury Secretary's daughter, they are unexpectedly invited to the family's home, where a
weekend of farcical events changes their perspectives on love and marriage.
The film opened on July 15, 2005, through New Line Cinema to critical and commercial
success, grossing $288.5 million worldwide on a $40 million budget.
It was the 6th highest grossing film of 2005 in the United States and became the
first R-rated comedy to make $200 million at the domestic box office.
The success of the film has been credited with helping to revive
the popularity of adult-oriented, R-rated comedies.
The film explores themes of cake, sailing, fake identity, wedding, lying.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.